College English Test, Band 6,
Part 2, Listening Comprehension, Section A, Directions.
In this section, you will hear two long conversations.
At the end of each conversation, you will hear four questions.
Both the conversation and the questions will be spoken only once.
After you hear a question,
you must choose the best answer from the four choices marked A, B, C, and D.
Then mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet 1 with a single line through the
center. Conversation 1 How are you enjoying your new job?
So far so good.
I don't miss having managers who deliver blunt, harsh feedback in the name of
efficiency. From the way you described your last company, no wonder they had a
problem with high staff turnover.
I couldn't wait to get out of there once my contract expired.
The problem with a company culture that prizes directness above all else is that it
creates a toxic culture of brilliant jerks that drives people out and erodes itself
from within. My company's managers tend to be accommodating and kind, overlooking
mistakes or issues so as not to hurt feelings.
Issues often get ignored there until they build up and reach a crisis point.
That's not surprising.
My new company seems to employ a feedback policy that combines compassion and
directness. Employees have the power to speak up, give feedback,
disagree and discuss problems in real time.
It seems to help us to course correct,
and meet challenges while also building teams that collaborate and care for one
another. But that would be based on an atmosphere of mutual trust, wouldn't it?
Otherwise people might interpret feedback as some kind of personal attack.
True. Without an atmosphere of trust, feedback can create stress and self -doubt.
But I think when we get feedback from someone we trust, we understand that the
feedback isn't some kind of personal attack.
It's actually a kind of support because it's offered in the spirit of helping us
improve. I think sometimes people need to shift their mindsets around how they
receive feedback. Yes.
Constructive feedback, after all, is how we learn and grow.
It's the basis for healthy parenting, lasting friendships, career development and so
much more. If we shelter our children, friends and colleagues from information that
might enrich and enhance their lives, we're not being caring.
We're actually doing harm to them.
That's exactly right.
Questions 1 to 4 are based on the conversation you have just heard.
Question 1. How does the woman describe her previous company's culture?
Question 2. What does the man say about his company's managers?
Question 3. What does the woman say the employees in her new company can do?
Question What woman employees
Question 4. What does the man say about constructive feedback?
Conversation 2. How was your holiday?
Not too many other tourists around, were there?
No, very few, relatively.
But I found myself moving from one accommodation to another, trying to find the
perfect place. It made me realize that indecision is a big problem for me.
Instead of relaxing, I was looking for the best spot.
It seems you suffer from fear of better options.
I've read about it.
It describes this loop of indecision as part of our programming.
Essentially, have this tendency to keep stretching out the decision -making process,
because as human beings, we are hard -wired to optimize.
We have always looked to get the best things we can as a sort of survival of the
fittest. Optimizing isn't the problem, but rather the process that we go through.
Well, that makes me feel better.
But I think, to technology, we can make comparisons more easily and have more access
to choice and customization.
We can now see what we could have, how we might get it, and what others have that we
might want. We keep looking over and returning to the same options again and again.
Yes, fear of better options offers little benefit.
It's an ailment of abundance.
You must have choices to have that fear of missing out on better options.
Yes. I need to note when I'm about inconsequential things, I guess.
If I'm spending too much time worrying over what to have for lunch, I'm robbing
myself of the energy to focus on the things that matter.
Exactly. But for more important matters, think gut instinct might be overrated.
When you have 30 -odd options, trusting your gut is not practical.
What you need to do is research, have a process, invest time exploring your options,
and eliminate as many things as you can.
The most toxic part of decision -making is going over the same options time and time
again. Questions 5 to 8 are based on the conversation you have just heard.
Question 5. What does the man say about his holiday?
Question 6. What does the woman say people tend to do when making decisions?
Question 7. What has made decision -making increasingly difficult?
Question 8. According to the woman, what should people do when making important
decisions? Section B.
Directions. In this section, you will hear two passages.
At the end of each passage, you will hear three or four questions.
Both the passage and the questions will be spoken only once.
After you hear a question, you must choose the best answer from the four choices
marked A, B, C, and D.
Then mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet 1 with a single line through the
centre. Passage 1.
The role of homework in classrooms is not a new debate.
Many parents and teachers are ardent supporters of homework.
But do all students benefit from homework?
A 2006 research paper suggested some correlation between the amount of homework done
by a student and future academic achievement for middle and high school students.
But not so much for younger kids.
Stanford study in 2014 suggested that the same was true for students in California's
affluent communities.
The findings challenged the idea that homework was inherently good.
The researchers concluded that there was an upper limit to the correlation between
homework and achievement, suggesting that high school students shouldn't be doing
more than two hours of homework a night, and the most valuable kind of homework for
elementary level children was simply assigned free reading.
The topic gets more complicated when we talk about the divide between rural and
urban communities. Studies found that in remote areas, poor quality or lack of
access can put students at a disadvantage because 70 of teachers in these areas
assign homework that requires internet access.
But one in three households doesn't have internet.
Experts assert homework requiring the internet isn't fair.
While the debate continues about the effect of homework on academic achievements,
there are studies focusing on other benefits of homework.
A study in Germany found that homework could have an effect on students'
personalities, suggesting that doing homework might help kids to become more
conscientious and independent learners.
Questions 9 to 11 are based on the passage you have just heard.
Question 9. What did the 2006 research find about homework?
Question 10. What do experts think of homework requiring internet access?
Question 11. What conclusion could be drawn from the study in Germany?
Passage 2. Robert Goddard, an American born in 1882, is widely regarded as the
world's first rocket scientist.
At age 27, published his first book, in which he hypothesized that a rocket launched
from Earth could reach the Moon.
Like many visionaries, the young scientist encountered numerous skeptics.
In January 1920, the New York Times ridiculed Goddard's theory that rockets could be
utilized for space exploration.
49 years later, Apollo 11 reached the
and the famed newspaper published an apology to
Goddard launched his first rocket from an aunt's farm in his native Massachusetts in
March 1926. His maiden rocket voyage lasted a mere three seconds.
It scaled an altitude of only 12 meters.
Nonetheless, it was a milestone in rocket science.
Goddard later consulted with a weather expert and determined that the climate of New
Mexico was ideal for year -round rocket launches.
In 1930, Goddard and his family relocated there, to a remote valley in the southwest
of the country.
There, he established a laboratory and test range.
However, the ambitious scientist received negligible support from the government.
For four years, wealthy businessman Daniel Guggenheim provided Goddard with an
annual $25,000 grant to pursue his dreams.
Other rocket enthusiasts also raised funds for him.
Over time, Goddard's rockets grew more sophisticated and included the installation
of instruments. In spite of his many successes, was never able to interest the U.S.
military in rocket -propelled weapons.
He was granted over 200 patents and continued to pioneer rocket technology until his
death in 1945.
Questions 12 to 15 are based on the passage you have just heard.
Question 12. What do we learn about Goddard's idea of using rockets for space
exploration? Question 13.
What does the passage say about Goddard's first rocket launch?
Question 14. Why did Goddard move to New Mexico?
Question 15. What does the passage say about Goddard's Question Goddard's
achievements? Section C.
Directions. this section, will hear three recordings of lectures or talks, followed
by three or four questions.
The recordings will be played only once.
After you hear a question, you must choose the best answer from the four choices
marked A, B, C, and D.
Then mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet 1, with a single line through the
centre. Recording 1.
Working for a new venture comes with a lot of
There's instability, unclear responsibilities, and the need to be a master of all
trades. But the primary benefit is usually the passion and excitement associated
with playing a role in a promising new company.
The person to thank for that passion and excitement is almost always the
entrepreneur. There's something about the founder's energy and enthusiasm that
infects the rest of the team.
The willingness to take risks may inspire others to be more courageous.
The optimism and positivity may motivate people to focus less on trivial and
unimportant matters.
The celebration of milestones may prompt staff to be more grateful about their own
accomplishments and privileges.
What becomes set in the firm's culture is a contagious collection of affirmative and
positive emotions, which are usually shared among the team.
Science has already done a good job of proving the results that follow.
These include better processes, greater team cohesion, reduced conflict, and sharper
alertness. But what is yet to be demonstrated is whether the founder's passion leads
to increased team performance.
This was recently tested in research, which analyzed the teams of 73 new companies
across a range of industries, such as IT, medicine, and energy.
The CEOs were consulted once again years after the initial analysis, and most shared
their firm's performance reports so that their success could be more objectively
measured. Entrepreneurial teams generally progress through three phases.
first is inventing a product or service.
The second is founding the venture to sell that product or and the third is
developing the firm so it continues to grow.
The researchers discovered that when the team is passionate about the third phase,
developing the firm, there's a clear link to performance.
But the first phase, a passion for invention, is not a reliable indicator that the
firm will still be open for business a few years later.
Likewise, the second, the passion for founding the venture doesn't necessarily
translate into greater success.
The solution to great team performance stems from a willingness to recruit others
who could direct their passion towards the third phase of entrepreneurialism,
developing the business.
Employing more staff can in itself be a risk for an entrepreneur, as is paying them
big dollars to attract them.
On many occasions, the entrepreneurs reported not paying themselves a wage at all
initially in order to cover salaries and expenses.
Question 17. What has science demonstrated regarding the positive culture of a new
venture? Question 18.
What does the speaker say about entrepreneurs at the initial stage of a new venture?
Recording 2. Aging is a curious thing, and people's desire to beat it, and death,
has become an industry worth hundreds of billions of dollars.
Despite the huge investment into research, aging remains somewhat obscure,
although there are certain things researchers do understand.
They know that women tend to have longer lifespans, living on average six years
longer than men.
No one is really certain of the reason for although the speculation centers around
the idea that women are more capable of surviving or handling disease than men.
For virtually every disease, the effects are greater on men than they are on women.
Some suggest that women's immune systems benefit from their tendency to prioritize
and nurture social connections, but for me, this explanation is hardly convincing.
Researchers also know, to an extent, what causes aging.
For 60 years, it was believed that cells would continue to divide forever.
It was only uncovered in relatively recent times that older people's divide a
smaller number of times than younger people's.
Only cancer cells, in fact, are capable of dividing forever.
Human cells have a limited reproductive ability.
an extent, we can postpone the eventual stop of cells dividing through nutrition,
exercise, good sleep, and even relaxation techniques, but we cannot stop the aging
process. And researchers are yet to answer the ultimate question of why does the
ultimately fall to pieces?
In the opinion of some of the world's best scientific minds on the subject,
part of the reason we don't yet have an answer is because many researchers are
looking in the wrong direction.
Many public health policymakers believe that the resolution of age -associated
disease will tell us something fundamental about the aging process.
But, say some top scientists, that's completely erroneous.
They point to when the diseases of childhood were eliminated, but this did not
provide any insight into childhood development.
In the same way, the idea that the resolution of age -associated disease, like heart
disease and stroke, will inform us about aging is not based on sound science or
logic. At best, if the major causes of death in developed countries were eliminated,
this would only add a decade to average life expectancy.
But while there is money available to be spent on the search to understand the
secrets of aging will be ongoing.
Questions 19 to 21 are based on the recording you have just heard.
Question 19. What do we learn about the possible reason why women tend to live
longer? Question 20.
What is the recent discovery about human cells?
Question 21. do many public health policymakers believe?
Good afternoon. In today's talk, we will discuss how managers can get their staff to
do what they are asked.
Much to their frustration, managers often struggle to get their staff to comply with
even simple instructions.
Often they blame their employees.
They don't read emails.
They don't listen.
They don't care.
That kind of thing.
But according to recent research conducted in Australia, it looks like it's not the
employees' fault, but the managers'.
It's easy to understand why people sometimes disobey procedures intentionally.
Occasionally, it's because they're pressured to finish in a short time.
At other times, they may disagree with the spirit of the procedure.
The effort demanded, the time consumed, the lack of potential effectiveness.
And every now and then, they just don't want to, maybe deliberately or out of
stubbornness. So apart from that, what else gets in the way of procedural
compliance? The research scholars surveyed 152 blue collar workers from two separate
sites in the mining industry.
They asked the workers a range of procedure related questions, such as whether they
found the procedures useful, how confident they felt in their job, how comfortable
they were to speak up in the workplace, and how closely they followed any new
procedures set by their managers.
They were also asked to rate the extent to which they perceived their supervisors to
be helpful. That last statement was the most instructive because, as the researchers
found, there was a remarkably strong correlation between how helpful supervisors
were perceived to be and how likely their employees were to follow their directives.
Supervisors' helping behaviour was found to be motivational in nature.
It increased employees' perception of the likelihood of success in the attainment of
job goals and therefore, fostered a willingness to dedicate their effort and ability
to their work.
In short, managers should be ongoing role models for the change, as the saying goes,
do as I do, not as I say.
To affect behavioural change, what's most required is interaction and involvement,
the human touch, and naturally, processes that add value.
Although procedures are designed to guide and support employees' work, employees, it
seems, can't always be expected to comply with procedures that are not seen as
useful. And, of course,
managers shouldn't keep resending emails.
They're an effective tool for the sharing of data and reports, but they're a
hopeless tool if what a manager is desiring is a change in
22 to 25 are based on the recording you have just heard.
Question 22. Why are managers often frustrated with their employees?
Question 23. Why do employees sometimes disobey procedures intentionally?
Question 24. When are employees more likely to follow instructions, according to the
researchers? Question 25.
What does the speaker say about emails?
That's the end of comprehension.